See our family. And feel better about yours.
The Simpsons Movie is a animation, comedy, family
film directed by David Silverman.
After Homer accidentally pollutes the town's water supply, Springfield is encased in
a gigantic dome by the EPA and the Simpsons are declared fugitives.
Homer Simpson / Itchy / Barney / Abe Simpson / Stage Manager / Krusty the Clown / Mayor Quimby / Mayor's Aide / Multi-Eyed Squirrel / Panicky Man / Sideshow Mel / Mr. Teeny
/ EPA Official / Kissing Cop / Bear / Boy on Phone / NSA Worker / Officer / Santa's Little Helper / Squeaky-Voiced Teen (voice), played by Dan Castellaneta.
Marge Simpson / Selma Bouvier / Patty Bouvier (voice), played by Julie Kavner.
Bart Simpson / Maggie Simpson / Ralph / Nelson / Todd Flanders / TV
Daughter / Woman on Phone (voice), played by Nancy Cartwright.
Lisa Simpson (voice), played by Yeardley Smith.
Professor Frink / Comic Book Guy / Moe / Chief Wiggum / Lou / Carl / Cletus / Bumblebee Man / Male EPA Worker / Dome Depot Announcer / Kissing Cop /
Carnival Barker / Counter Man / Apu / Drederick Tatum / Sea Captain / EPA Passenger / Robot / Dr. Nick / Wise Guy (voice), played by Hank Azaria.
Scratchy / Mr. Burns / Rev. Lovejoy / Ned Flanders / Lenny / Skull / President Arnold Schwarzenegger / Kent Brockman /
Principal Skinner / Dr. Hibbert / Smithers / Toll Booth Man / Guard / Otto / Kang (voice), played by Harry Shearer.
The Simpsons Movie is a 2007 American animated comedy film based on the
animated television series The Simpsons created by Matt Groening.
The film was directed by David Silverman and stars Dan Castellaneta, Julie Kavner, Nancy Cartwright, Yeardley Smith, Hank Azaria, Harry Shearer, Pamela Hayden,
Tress MacNeille, Joe Mantegna, and other recurring actors reprising their roles from the series, with Albert Brooks and Tom Hanks joining for the film.
The plot follows the Simpson family as they grapple with the fallout of Homer Simpson's reckless actions, which lead to Springfield being imprisoned under a
massive glass dome by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the family's eviction from the town, and a strain on their relationship with him.
Although previous attempts to create a Simpsons film had been made,
they failed due to the lack of a final screenplay.
In 2001, after the voice cast agreed to do the film,
series producers Groening, James L.
Brooks, Al Jean, Mike Scully and Richard Sakai began development on the film: a writing team of Brooks, Groening, Jean, Scully, Ian
Maxtone-Graham, George Meyer, David Mirkin, Mike Reiss, Matt Selman, John Swartzwelder, and Jon Vitti was assembled.
They conceived numerous plot ideas, and one of
Groening's was ultimately adapted.
The screenplay was rewritten over a hundred times, which continued
after work on the film's animation began in 2006.
Hans Zimmer composed the score the for the film while Green Day
performed a rock version of the shows theme.
Consequently, hours of finished material was cut from the final release, including cameo roles from Erin Brockovich, Minnie
Driver, Isla Fisher, Edward Norton, and Kelsey Grammer, who would have reprised his role as Sideshow Bob.
Green Day and Tom Hanks voice their own animated
counterparts in the film's final cut.
The Simpsons Movie premiered in Springfield, Vermont on July 21, 2007, and was
theatrically released in the United States on July 27, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who praised its story, writing, humor, and animation, and was a commercial success, grossing $536.4 million worldwide against a production budget of $75 million, becoming the eighth-highest-grossing film of 2007, as
well as at the time the second-highest-grossing traditionally animated film and the highest-grossing film based on an animated television series, two records later overtaken by Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba – The Movie: Infinity Castle in 2025.
The film was nominated for numerous awards, including a Golden Globe Award for
Best Animated Feature Film at the 65th Golden Globe Awards.
A sequel is scheduled for release on September 3, 2027.
The film explores themes of garbage, pollution, quarantine,
environmental protection agency, parent child relationship.
The tone is lighthearted.